[theme music playing]
[Emilia] You know what to do.
Finish her off.
-[gunshot rings out]
-Get out of here.
Don't ever come back
to Poblacion Ardiente.
[Raul] You killed them all off?
A whole family?
You didn't even spare the kid.
Do you know the way to San Marcelino?
How do I get there?
[tricycle driver] Hop in. Come on.
Mister, I'm going to get out!
[blows whistle]
[Jepoy] There are lots of thugs
around here.
Anyway, I gotta go. I'm the parking boy!
-Jepoy.
-[car horn honking]
[Diego] To the people
who know where Lily is…
[Julio] Idiot! You caused a huge scandal!
People are talking about
a child who's gone missing
from Poblacion Ardiente!
[Prianka] You can't go back to Ardiente
while you're still weak.
I want justice for my parents!
[in English] Then we have a deal.
[in Taglish] I've adopted you.
You'll be called Ivy Aguas.
-Something grew.
-A lone blossom. [English] A wildflower.
[in Tagalog] What's important
is it can thrive anywhere.
-It can survive in any weather.
-[inaudible]
[Ivy] This was the only way
for me to be reborn.
To become a new me.
Remember everything I taught you.
Do what you must do.
Make them pay.
[Ivy] I made a promise to my parents.
Now, I promise you. I'll make them pay.
[music ends]
PRIANKA P. AGUAS
[melancholic music playing]
[Dante] There'll be fewer
street kids in town now!
-Dad.
-Dante.
[both sob]
-Lily, get out of here!
-What happened to you?
-[shushes]
-Hey!
Lily. Run!
[woman] Can you kill her?
[man] The governor and mayor
will kill us if we let her go.
-Get out!
-Mom. Mom.
You killed my husband!
-Dad, please stop!
-[grunting]
Dad!
That's enough!
-Viva Ardiente!
-[crowd] Viva Ardiente!
-[Julio] Viva Ardiente!
-Viva Ardiente!
-[crowd] Viva Ardiente!
[crowd whooping, applauding]
[wailing]
[yowls]
[tense music playing]
WELCOME TO ARDIENTE TOWN
[in English] Hello, Poblacion Ardiente.
[in English] I'm back.
Who's she?
[phone ringing]
Hello? Okay. I'm on my way home. Okay.
Back to the house. Hurry.
[tense music playing]
UPCOMING EVENT
ARDIENTE TRADE EXPO 2017
ARDIENTE OPENS ITS DOORS
TO ALL ENTREPRENEURS AND INVESTORS
SIGNAL LOST
PLEASE TRY AGAIN LATER
GOV. EMILIA AND CONG. JULIO ARDIENTE
MAYOR ARNALDO ARDIENTE-TORILLO
WELCOME
GOV. EMILIA ARDIENTE
-Well? You scoundrel!
-[Raul grunting]
I think you revel in testing my patience!
-Get up!
-[groans]
I honestly can't stand imbeciles like you!
-Papa!
-Do you want to get hit, too?
No, I just want to remind you
what the doctor said.
[in English] That you need to calm down!
[in Taglish] You need to be healthy
for the national campaign.
[in English] Calm down? Calm down?
[in Tagalog] Because of your husband here,
there might not even be a campaign!
[in English] What? Why? What happened?
You…
You better turn over the money
by next week!
Understood?
Imbecile!
ARDIENTE TOWN
[Arnaldo] The documents
have to be processed soon
so I can sign them right away.
-Yes, Mayor.
-[woman] The mayor's here!
-The mayor's here.
-Hello, Mayor!
Good afternoon, Mayor!
Good afternoon, everyone.
Wow, Mayor. You're so handsome!
Can I give you a kiss?
[woman giggles]
-Please step away, ma'am.
-Hold on.
No, it's okay. It's okay.
Well…
I'm sorry I can't stay long.
-I have to be somewhere.
-Sure. Thank you, Mayor!
[woman] You smell so nice, Mayor!
He smells good!
[unintelligible dialogue]
-Mayor.
-Give me that.
Why do they have to kiss me so hard?
We haven't even left yet.
Who knows what kind of infection
they've given me. Dammit.
Mayor, Perez's men asked me
to give you this.
ROLEX
It's authentic.
This is pretty expensive.
Perez must badly want me
to approve his project now.
Mayor, Mr. Fernan texted. We're needed--
Make them wait!
This is Diego's fault.
This was all his idea.
He's starting to think like a hillbilly.
Spending time with those farmers.
Let's go. Let's get this over with.
Let's go, Mike.
[crowd cheering]
ROAD CLOSED
[woman speaking unintelligibly]
[crowd cheering]
-Excuse me, sir.
-Yes, ma'am?
Is this the way
to the Ardiente Garden Resort?
Yes, ma'am, but the road is closed.
-Just take the other road. Gotta go.
-Thank you.
[crowd cheering]
BURAK-RAKAN TOURNAMENT
[action music playing]
[crowd cheering]
Get up!
["Sa'Yo" instrumental music playing]
[crowd cheering]
[woman] One!
-Countdown!
-[all] Two!
[all] Three!
[cheering, whooping]
[all chanting] Diego!
[Pandoy] Ladies and gentlemen.
Our champion for this year!
Not only did he display
strength and wit in battle,
he also showed that he is one
with the people of Ardiente!
The one and only.
Diego Ardiente…
Torillo!
[all chanting] Diego!
It's Diego.
That's him. My best friend.
[young Diego] Lily.
Thanks for helping me out.
[young Lily] No worries. I got you!
[shouting, in English] Thank you, Lily!
[shouting, in English]
You're welcome, Diego!
-Like that?
-[both laughing]
-Let's go!
-Let's go there!
[crowd chanting] Diego!
Now… [clears throat]
as per tradition, it's time
for you to give these flowers
to the person you'd like
to dedicate your victory to.
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[crowd chanting] Diego!
[chanting] Diego!
-[Loring giggles]
-[Pandoy laughs]
-[Pandoy] Diego!
-[crowd applauding]
[Loring] Hey!
[in English] Miss! Miss!
[in Taglish] Miss, wait up!
-[in English] Miss?
-[in English] Yes?
Uh…
[stutters] For you.
Oh!
[in English] Sorry.
[in Tagalog] Thank you.
[Pandoy] Diego! Hey, Diego.
Diego, your brother's here.
Who's she?
[car engine starts]
I don't know.
-I didn't get her name.
-[scoffs]
Always the slowpoke. Come on!
Hey!
[sighs]
[Arnaldo] I promise you.
[in Taglish] Constructing an export
processing zone in our town
will only help flourish
the co-op my brother started.
[crowd applauding]
Everyone's life will prosper.
Here's to a more progressive
Poblacion Ardiente!
[crowd cheering, applauding]
To a brighter and better future
for all of us!
-[crowd cheers, whoops]
-Long live the mayor!
-[chuckles]
Thank you! Thank you so much.
-[Arnaldo] Thank you.
-[man] Mayor!
-[woman] Well done!
-Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thanks, Mayor!
[chuckles]
You're lucky you weren't struck
by lightning.
How many decades has our family
been telling these people
that their lives will get better?
At least I don't have to roll
in the mud to make them love me.
[sighs] Oh, well. Let's go.
It's good we were able
to get a hold of these
so I can make a nice snack.
-You picked nice ones, too.
-Goodness, Diego!
-Nanny Loring!
-Hi, Diego!
There you are! I thought you went home
after the wrestling match.
Wait. Who was the girl
you gave the flowers to?
Don't nag him.
He didn't even get her name.
I think she was a tourist.
Someone who lost her way.
Oh. A wildflower for a lost lady.
-Ah.
-You're just jealous.
-Jealous?
-Someone's jealous.
-Is that true?
-No, I'm not!
[both chuckling]
-But Nanny Loring.
-No, I'm not.
I just always give you
the flowers whenever I win.
-Mm-hm.
-I wanted to turn things around.
-[in English] For a change.
-[in English] Yeah.
[in English] For a change. Change is good.
[Loring, in English] For a change?
[in Tagalog] Stop messing around.
-That hurt.
-Stop making fun of me.
-Well, speaking of change.
-Yeah?
[in Taglish] What is this
export processing plant
your brother told us about?
Explain it to us.
I'm not sure, either.
But don't worry. I'll find out.
Ever since he became mayor,
everyone's lives seemed
to get better, didn't it?
But let's not forget how important it is
that Diego founded the cooperative
once he graduated college.
[in English] Of course.
And we'll only make it flourish.
[in Taglish] And if his export
processing plant can help,
then that'll be great for all of us.
Maybe. Maybe your brother's
changed for the better.
I think he changed
after studying in America.
Sometimes,
I forget all those times
he used to make my blood boil.
[both chuckle]
-Just admit it.
-That?
You're smitten by the mayor's charisma.
Did he get any more handsome
since you left the mansion?
No, no! No one's as handsome
as my dearest Diego.
[Pandoy stutters] What about me?
You? Wow.
-Now, who's jealous?
-You wish. You're too old!
-Why don't you spill it?
-What?
-Admit it.
-Admit what?
You'd run inside with just
a towel on when I'd come around.
You'd even squeal, too.
Why were you always passing
by our backyard, anyway?
[Pandoy] Well, I was a bit
of a Peeping Tom.
ARDIENTE GARDEN RESORT
[in English] Thank you.
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
[Pandoy] Diego Ardiente-Torillo!
Please get my things from the trunk.
Yes, ma'am.
-Miss, wait up!
-[in English] Yes?
[stutters] For you.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Yes, I've just arrived.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
All right, bye.
[instrumental theme music playing]
365 DAYS OF LOVE AND GUIDANCE
-365 days?
-For a year filled with love.
[instrumental theme music playing]
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
ARDIENTE GARDEN RESORT
[suspenseful music playing]
Dad?
-Dad?
-[Dante] Lily, listen.
Dad. Dad.
Promise me that you won't let yourself
be abused or harassed by anyone.
Yes, I promise, Dad.
Dad? Dad!
-Dad.
-[Camia] Lily?
-Mom?
-Lily.
Lily, I'm begging you. Leave this place!
-Mom.
-Please!
Mom! No.
Mom!
Mom! Mom? Mom?
-[shushes]
-Mom!
-You need to go.
-Mom, what's happening?
-Run.
-Hey!
Lily. Run!
[gasps]
[pensive music playing]
Boss.
Sir, we only--
[grunts]
Sir! Sir.
[groans and grunts]
What? You want some? Come here.
What's this? One bag?
Sorry, boss.
[grunts]
The next time you bring me
something like this,
you'll have it worse. I don't want this!
I want sacks of it! Do you understand?
-Yes, sir!
-Take them to the car.
[suspenseful music playing]
Grandpa.
Good evening.
So you still come home here.
I still live here.
You're my family. I'm still an Ardiente.
They say you won the tournament.
[scoffs]
Don't be surprised, Diego.
This town is mine.
It's only normal that I know
what happens in this place.
The fight was close.
So, that's where your interest lies.
Rolling in mud.
Like I told you once before.
[in Taglish] Some people
are only meant to be…
worker ants.
[in Tagalog] I guess that's all you are.
I think it's better.
At least one Ardiente
can stand with the people.
Right, sir?
I'll go rest now, Grandpa.
Where have you been?
Do you think I don't notice
that you're always missing?
Is it a woman again?
You don't have to kill anyone.
[in Taglish] You're the only one Dad
is depending on for his campaign funds.
My fundraisers don't get enough money,
even though they're legal.
This is your only job,
and you can't even do it well.
[in English] You know, sometimes
I wonder why I keep you around!
We both know the reason.
It's because you love me.
[grunts]
[suspenseful music playing]
[phone ringing]
Mayor. Yes, I'm on my way.
-[melancholic music playing]
-[Ivy sobbing]
[Dante] I want you to learn
how to protect yourself
because your Mom and I
won't always be by your side.
Promise me you won't let yourself
be abused or harassed by anyone.
-Get out!
-Mom.
You killed my husband!
Dad, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry it's been so long
since I came here…
to finally visit your grave.
[weeps]
Dad.
Dad, I promise…
I will not leave this town…
until I find out…
why this happened to you…
and to Mom.
I swear to you and Mom.
That's becoming your habit.
It helps me sleep.
Is this about Dad again?
[in English] After all this time,
you still let him get to you.
-Arnaldo.
-[in Taglish] What did he do this time?
[in Taglish] You know,
your father is just frustrated.
[in English] He's frustrated?
What about you? Are you frustrated?
[in Tagalog] Do you hate that Grandpa
made me run for mayor instead of him?
[in Taglish] No, I'm just saying
you have to understand your father.
Understand him?
Mom, he doesn't have the Ardiente blood!
Grandpa himself said
the strength of Poblacion Ardiente
comes from our blood!
We gave him a chance, but what happened?
[in Taglish] He ran for councilor
and lost! And mind you, he lost miserably!
[in English] Now,
we can't let that bring us down!
No, we can't let him bring us down!
[in Tagalog] What about
the people of Ardiente?
What about us and all we've worked for?
[in English] Now, the sooner
he realizes that, the better!
[in Taglish] The sooner everyone will be
at peace, especially you!
[in English] I worry about you.
Son.
Don't worry, I can handle it.
[phone ringing]
Hello.
[in Taglish] Yes, I'm at the cemetery.
Yes, I know it's dangerous.
I'm on my way out.
Dad, I'll be back.
-Mayor.
-What?
Were you asleep when I called?
No, I just checked something out.
[in Taglish] I just saw the floor plans
for the export processing zone.
SITE PLAN
It looks like it needs a lot of land.
[in English] Yes, I know.
Why don't we use the lot
of the cooperative?
You're good. I like you.
It hasn't been a year since
the headquarters in Manila sent you,
but you're hardworking,
reliable, and trustworthy.
Thank you, Mayor.
But won't this cause a problem with Diego?
He doesn't need to find out just yet.
I'll take care of it.
ARDIENTE GARDEN RESORT
-Nanny Carlotta?
-I was so worried about you.
I couldn't rest without you by my side.
Nanny Carlotta!
Don't tell me I have
nothing to worry about.
You went to the cemetery last night,
even though it was dangerous!
You made me so nervous.
Don't make me go back to Manila.
I want to stay here with you.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you.
Or that you'll lose yourself
now that you're back in this town.
Arnaldo.
Diego, you're here!
I thought you slept at your nanny's.
Well, I just picked up some things.
By the way, it's a good thing
we saw each other.
[in Taglish] About the export
processing plant.
How will that help my men
at the cooperative?
Diego, don't rush things, okay?
I'll tell you the plan
when the time is right.
Okay. I'll go ahead.
Hey, wait! Maybe you'd like
to have some coffee?
You can update me
on your progress at the co-op.
[in Taglish] Maybe next time.
All right.
ARDIENTE EXPORT PROCESSING PLANT
What about the house in Manila?
I closed it off.
I gave everyone a vacation.
[chuckles]
Nanny Carlotta, it's only been a few days,
and you're like this already.
That's exactly it.
I'm so happy you're still alive.
Yes, I am. Let's talk about things later.
You should get some rest.
I have some errands to run.
-I'll go with you!
-Nanny Carlotta.
Please let me do this.
Okay.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Dante] This is going to be our new home!
We'll have the peaceful life
you've been dreaming of.
[tense music playing]
Lily. Run!
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[young Lily] Go, Diego! Diego! Duck!
-[both] Yay!
-That was amazing, Diego!
I know Lily will come back someday.
I can feel it.
She'll come back here.
[birds chirping]
[Diego] I know Lily will come back
someday. I can feel it.
Fried bananas! Bananas!
Deliciously made fritters!
Bananas… Oh, gosh.
[Loring] Uh…
Were you here
at the tournament the other day?
Somebody handed you flowers, right?
[in Taglish] Oh. You're beautiful
in person. I mean, up close.
[comical music playing]
Why are you staring like that?
Huh?
Um…
I'm sorry, I just remembered something.
Oh, you remember
when you looked in the mirror?
That beautiful face! [laughs]
Come on, pretty woman.
Buy some fritters! These are yummy.
You know, a teacher taught me
how to make these.
She used to run a daycare.
Will you buy some? How many?
Come on, lady. I swear, they're delicious.
-I'm sorry, I'm on a diet.
-What?
I have to go.
[in English] Miss.
-I'm sorry. I'll buy next time.
-Ma'am.
On a diet, huh?
Hey! Did you get her name?
She didn't even buy my fritters.
How could I start
chatting with her? My goodness!
You're the queen of gossip,
so that's impossible.
-That's not true!
-[Pandoy] You're getting old.
You're the nosy one!
-You're old!
-Pandoy!
-Fernan!
-Hey, Mister Fernan!
How was it? Any news?
[in Taglish] I didn't get updates
on the Mayor's export processing zone.
Seems like nobody's aware of that.
Diego, have you talked to your brother?
You're stressing yourself out too much.
If there are no updates yet,
then it's okay.
Arnaldo said there are
no concrete plans yet.
So I think it might take a while.
See, there's no plan yet, so just relax.
[Loring] That's right. Here.
-Have some fritters.
-Yes.
-[Pandoy chuckles]
-Did you add jackfruit?
[Ivy exhales sharply]
[groans]
I never thought that…
[exhales sharply]
I never thought that
it would be this hard.
I thought seeing our house
would fuel my anger
and make me tougher.
But when I actually saw it…
it just…
It hurts even more.
Then, I saw Miss Loring earlier.
Did she recognize you?
No. Because they only know Lily.
To all of them…
Lily is dead.
[Carlotta] Now, Ivy is here,
to seek justice for Lily's parents.
[tense music playing]
[Prianka] You must know your enemies, Ivy.
Both in business and in life.
Know every single detail about them.
Every bit of information
you get will be helpful.
Sometimes, you need to turn
your enemies into allies
to get what you want.
[in English] Intelligence is not enough.
You need to be wise.
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] Emilia is the key
to what happened to Mom.
But you? You are the key to Emilia.
I'll start with you.
[tense music playing]
[Arnaldo] Do you know you're trespassing?
[in English] This is private property.
[in English] Mr. Mayor,
my name is Ivy. Ivy Aguas.
[Ivy in Tagalog] I've laid the trap.
All we need is for him
to walk right into it.
If we look at the status of her assets,
she can be an investor here in Ardiente.
-[in English] Good work.
-[Ivy] Whose house is that?
[in Taglish] What will it take, Mr. Mayor,
to make this property mine?
-[in English] Dinner with the family.
-Isn't that too fast?
[Ivy] I'll find out the truth
about what you had to do
with my mother's death.
[in English] You must be Ivy.
[theme music playing]